## **Nemat Aloush**

A **Data Scientist** (Python, and SQL) with over two years of experience working with international teams. Graduated in the top 10% of the class with a B.Sc. in Software Engineering. Soon to graduate with a M.Sc. in Applied Mathematics and Informatics.

Saint Petersburg, Russia

memat.aloush@gmail.com

in <u>LinkedIn/nemat.aloush</u>

GitHub/nemat.aloush

Portfolio/nemat.aloush

### **EDUCATION**

**ITMO University**, Master's degree in Applied Mathematics and Informatics – Machine Learning and Big Data Analysis Technologies.

The degree is completely in English

SEP 2021 - JUL 2023

<u>Multivariate Data Analysis Project</u>. Analyzing a real-world dataset by studying univariate and multivariate random variables, sampling, and forecasting using Python.

## **HIAST Institution**, Bachelor's degree in Software Engineering.

Graduated in the top 10% of the class.

OCT 2015 - SEP 2020

<u>Semantic Search Engine Project</u>. Developed a semantic search engine in English to search among news imported from the BBC. The engine was developed using Java and applying Natural Language Processing and Information Retrieval concepts.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Syrian Virtual University, Damascus, Syria — Teacher Assistant

Providing virtual education to students from around the world. APR 2021 - SEP 2021

- Teaching basic concepts in algorithm thinking and C# programming language to first-year students in the Information Technology program.
- Evaluating 120 students' individual final projects.
- Member of a team of two professors and three other engineers.
- Regularly taught the course remotely.

# <u>Syriatel Mobile Telecom</u>, Damascus, Syria — *Software Engineer, Student Internship*

A telecommunications company in Syria.

JUL 2019 - SEP 2019

- Developed a <u>Social Network Analysis system</u> in R programming language as a fourth-year academic project. The project served to guide any user with no experience to discover social networks.
- Worked under the supervision of two academic supervisors and one technical supervisor.
- Ranked first in my academic fourth year, based on the grade of the project and other academic courses.

### **STACK**

**Proficient:** Python, SQL, C#, C++, Java, Pandas, NumPy, Jupyter, GitHub.

**Good**: PHP, JavaScript, MySQL, Git, Skearn, SciPy, Keras, TensorFlow.

Familiar: R, Kubernetes, Spark

#### **LANGUAGES**

Arabic native
English fluent
German beginner
French beginner
Russian beginner



Talent without Borders.
Imagine Foundation e.V.
joinimagine.org

10/14/2022

### **Recommendation letter for Nemat Aloush**

Dear colleague -

I hope this finds you well.

I'm writing to you to **strongly endorse Nemat Aloush** for a technical role in your company.

We are a social venture that supports young aspiring talents from non-European countries in finding a challenging tech job in Europe or North America. We run a highly selective 4 week digital boot camp for full stack developers, data scientists/engineers and software automation testers. Over the course of the program, we identify candidates whose talent, passion and work ethic significantly stand out from their peers.

## Nemat Aloush is an outstanding Data scientist who ranks in the top 10% of our peer group.

English communication Strong – validated in multiple rounds of 1:1 interviews

Technical skills High & up to date – on par with candidates in Germany

Unique qualities Academic excellence (top 10% of class)

EU 'Blue Card' eligibility Yes - Degree needs review - run a quick check via Anabin DB

Maturity Junior – 1 year of work experience

Please feel free to reach out to me personally at <u>johann@joinimagine.org</u> in case of any questions.

Warm regards & herzliche Grüße -

Dr. Johann Daniel Harnoss

JoGun Hary S

Founder & CEO